Guide to the Major Speakers Committee Records, 1956-2003
Duke University. University Archives
Major Speakers Committee 1956-2003
Duke University. University Archives
Duke University. Union. Major Speakers Committee
4.25 linear feet Extent: approx. 4,000 Items
Major Speakers is a committee of Duke University Union. Formerly the Educational Affairs Committee, the Major Speakers Committee is responsible for bringing to campus figures of national and international significance to speak upon the complex problems of the times. The collection contains files about speakers brought to the Duke Campus by the Major Speakers committee of Duke University Union. Materials present include administrative documents including budgets, policy notices, correspondence, performance contracts, publicity materials, and clippings. Dates in the collection range from 1956-2003.
UA.09.13.0004
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Provenance
The Major Speakers Committee were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1973-2007.
Historical Note
Major Speakers is a committee of Duke University Union. Formerly the Educational Affairs Committee, the Major Speakers Committee is responsible for bringing to campus figures of national and international significance to speak upon the complex problems of the times. The committee also sponsors three other series: an Adventure series dedicated to the presentation of noted explorers, sociologists, and anthropologists through film and lecture; a seminar series highlighting significant problems of society, and faculty lectures.
Duke University Union was founded in 1954, as the Duke Student Union, with the purpose of promoting the social, recreational, cultural, educational, and spiritual activities of the students. The Union consists of the following committees and programs: ACE (All Campus Events); Broadway at Duke; Cable13; the Coffeehouse; Freewater Presentations; Freewater Productions, Major Attractions; Major Speakers; Small Town Records; Visual Arts; and WXDU.
Collection Overview
The collection contains files about speakers brought to the Duke campus by the Major Speakers Committee of Duke University Union. Materials present include administrative documents including budgets, policy notices, correspondence, performance contracts, publicity materials, and clippings. The collection is arranged into the following groupings subject files, and speakers. Dates in the collection range from 1956-2003.
Subject Headings
Duke University. Union; Speeches, addresses, etc. -- Universities and colleges; Clippings
Related Material
Duke University Union records, 1951-
University Archives. Duke University.
Major Attractions Committee records, 1957-1995
University Archives, Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Subject Files
  - Adventure Series, 1964-1968 (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Alumni Series, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Black History Month, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Budget, 1972-1993 (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - Chair Applications, 2002-2003 (Box 1)
  - Committee Members, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1974-1984 (5 folders) (Box 1)
  - Cosponsorhips, 1983-1993 (8 folders) (Box 1)
  - Educational Affairs Committee, 1962; 1965 (Box 1)
  - Evaluations, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
  - Fall Schedule, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Famous Signatures (Box 1)
  - Fees for Contracts, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
  - Financial Reports, 1988-1989 (Box 1)
  - Future, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
  - General, 1956-1995 (23 folders) (Box 2)
  - Invitations, 1971-1977 (4 folders) (Box 2)
  - Members, 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Minutes, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 1969-1993 (3 folders) (Box 2)
  - Past Speakers,1956-1977 (Box 2)
  - Policy/Prevention Multiple Invites to Speakers, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Potential Speakers, 1988-1994 (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Presidential Candidates and Journalist Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Press Release/Schedule, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Publicity, 1993-1994 (Box 2)
  - Regrets, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
  - Rejected Offers, 1991-1992 (Box 2)
  - Various, 1989-1992 (2 folders) (Box 2)
- Speakers
  - William Buckley, 1961-1969 (Box 3)
  - Ambassador Tran Van Chuong, 1964 February 14 (Box 3)
  - Lester Maddox, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Dean Rusk, 1968-1970 (Box 3)
  - Senator John S. Tower, 1969 November 10 (Box 3)
  - Senator George McGovern, 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - In Nhel and Uk Someth, 1970 November 19 (Box 3)
  - Robert Finch, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Mrs. Coretta Scott King, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Senator John Tower, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Shirley Chisolm, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Senator Edmund Muskie, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
  - Barry Goldwater, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
  - Dr. Sam Keene, circa 1970 or 1971 March 16 (Box 3)
  - Dr. Eugene Schoenfeld, 1971 February 8 (Box 3)
  - Muriel Fox, [1971] March 9 (Box 3)
  - Senator Marlon Cook, 1971 May 10 (Box 3)
  - Tom Wicker, 1971 May 12 (Box 3)
  - Senator Birch Bayh, 1971 September 22 (Box 3)
  - Senator and Mrs. Fred Harris, 1971 October 18 (Box 3)
  - Henry M. Jackson, Nicholas Johnson, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Paul McCloskey, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
  - Norman Mailer, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
  - Mr. William Kunster, 1972 January 20 (Box 3)
  - Bill Russell, 1972 March 1 (Box 3)
  - Dr. Rollo May, 1972 March 14 (Box 3)
  - B. F. Skinner, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Dick Gregory, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Imamu Baraka, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Senator Thomas Eagleton, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Dr. Jewell Gresham and Ms. Gloria Steinem, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - Robert Hyslop, SEATO (South-East Asia Treaty Organization), 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - Malcolm X (documentary), 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - Ramsey Clark, 1973 April 19 (Box 3)
  - R. Buckminister Fuller, 1973 October 2 (Box 3)
  - Tom Wolfe, 1973 November 13 (Box 3)
  - Stuart Udall, 1973 October 22 (Box 3)
  - John Rechy, 1973 Dec. 4 (Box 3)
  - John Beecher, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Senator Edward Kennedy, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Senator Sam Ervin and Samuel Dash, 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - John Houseman, 1974 Jan. 29 (Box 3)
  - C. Vann Woodward, 1974 Apr. 19 (Box 3)
  - Cesar Chavez, 1974 Sept. 11 (Box 3)
  - William F. Buckley, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Hunter Thompson, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Milton Friedman, 1975 January 24 (Box 3)
  - Frederic Storaska, 1975 February 12; 1977 September 20 (Box 3)
  - James Doohan, 1976-1979 (Box 3)
  - John Kolisch, 1977 September 29 (Box 3)
  - Nikki Giovanni, 1977 October 10 (Box 3)
  - Energy Symposium Speakers, 1977 October 31-November 3 (Box 4)
  - Tom Wicker, 1977 December 8 (Box 4)
  - Admiral H. G. Rickover, United States Navy, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Ambassador Andrew Young, 1977-1978 (Box 4)
  - Henry Kyemba, 1978 February 14 (Box 4)
  - Ronald K. Wright, M. D., 1978 March 22 (Box 4)
  - Arthur Knight, 1978 October 11 (Box 4)
  - Admiral Turner, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Clovis Maksoud, 1978 (Box 4)
  - William Kunstler, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Bob Woodward, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Leonard Feather, 1978-1979 (Box 4)
  - Frederic Storaska, 1978-1979; 1980 October 9 (Box 4)
  - Dick Cavett, 1979 October 5 (Box 4)
  - George Plimpton, 1979 (Box 4)
  - 51 Athletics Speakers Bureau, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Abba Eban (Israel's former Foreign Minister), 1979-1980 (Box 4)
  - Robert Evans, 1980 February 20 (Box 4)
  - Rabbi Meir Kahane, 1980 February 26 (Box 4)
  - Rev. Martin Luther King, Sr., 1980 April 4 (Box 4)
  - Dr. Juanita Kreps, 1980 September 15 (Box 4)
  - James Hall, 1980 October 24 (Box 4)
  - David Fry, 1980 November 6 (Box 4)
  - Storaska, 1980 October 9 (Box 4)
  - Greensboro, a rational discussion, 1980 December 4 (Box 4)
  - Journalist Forum, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Indian Heritage Week, 1980-1981 (Box 4)
  - Women's Awareness Week, 1980-1981 (Box 4)
  - Greensboro Forum, 1980-1981 (Box 4)
  - Symposium, 1980-1981 (Box 4)
  - Journalist's Forum, 1981 January 23 (Box 4)
  - Wilson Bryan Key, 1981 January 27 (Box 4)
  - David Halberstam, 1981 January 27; 1985 November 19 (Box 4)
  - Morefield-White, 1981, April 1 (Box 4)
  - Richard Morefield, 1981 April 13 (Box 4)
  - Ambassador Robert White, 1981 April 14 (Box 4)
  - April Speaker, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Meyers, 1981 October (Box 4)
  - Timothy Leary, 1981 November 4 (Box 5)
  - Isaac B. Singer, 1981 November 9 (Box 5)
  - Lisa Birnbach's Preppie Program, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Sanford Student Talk, 1981-1982 (Box 5)
  - Gordon Adams, 1982 February 9 (Box 5)
  - Sam Cook, 1982 March 1 (Box 5)
  - Chris Edwards, 1982 March 3 (Box 5)
  - Chaim Potok, 1982 April 5 (Box 5)
  - John Anderson, 1982, September 16 (Box 5)
  - Alan Cranston, 1982 October 22 (Box 5)
  - Abbie Hoffman, 1982 October 26 (Box 5)
  - Joe Jackson, 1982 November 30 (Box 5)
  - Susan Sontag, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Forum for Democracy, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Native American Awareness Week, circa 1982 (Box 5)
  - Ted Turner, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Jenny Teplitz, 1982 Fall (Box 5)
  - Steve Bell, 1983 January 27 (Box 5)
  - General Duke, 1983 March 31 (Box 5)
  - Daniel Yergin, 1983 April 13 (Box 5)
  - Antoinette Handy, 1983 September 19 (Box 5)
  - Cesar Chavez/Dolores Huerta, 1983 September 22 (Box 5)
  - Vinicio Cerezo, 1983 October 21 (Box 5)
  - G. Gordon Liddy, 1983 October 24 (Box 5)
  - Marco Vinicio Cerezo Arevalo, 1983 October 27 (Box 5)
  - Alberto Arene, 1983 October 31 (Box 5)
  - English Seminar, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Senator Jesse Helms, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Nelson N. Johnson, circa 1983 (Box 5)
  - Peace-Making in a Nuclear World Symposium, 1983-1984 (Box 5)
  - Tom Jackson, 1984 November 28 (Box 5)
  - Zoe Walker, 1984 February 7 (Box 5)
  - Jabberwocky Humor Extravaganza, 1984 February 17 (Box 5)
  - Nuclear Symposium, 1984 February (Box 5)
  - Earthwalk, 1984 March 28 (Box 5)
  - Kodak Presentation, 1984 March 28 (Box 5)
  - Shere Hite, 1984 April 4 (Box 5)
  - General Bernard Rogers, 1984 October 18 (Box 5)
  - Dr. Ruth Westheimer, 1984 September 18 (Box 5)
  - Father Andrew Greeley, 1984 November 15 (Box 5)
  - Tom Jackson, 1984 November 28 (Box 5)
  - Letter to Buckley, circa 1984 (Box 5)
  - Candidate Forum, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Jim Hunt, circa 1984 (Box 6)
  - E.F. Hutton, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Bruce Payne/Leadership Program, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Siskel and Ebert, 1984-1985 (Box 6)
  - Morton Dean, 1985 January 30 (Box 6)
  - Jimmy Belushi, 1985 March 25 (Box 6)
  - Curtis and Lisa Sliwa, 1985 April 11 (Box 6)
  - General William Westmoreland, 1985 September 19 (Box 6)
  - Jeanne Kirkpatrick, circa 1985 (Box 6)
  - SAE Symposium: Athletics, 1985 (Box 6)
  - South Africa Symposium, circa 1985 (Box 6)
  - SDCA - Aldofo Calero, 1986 January 28 (Box 6)
  - Eleanor Smeal, 1986 April 10 (Box 6)
  - Julius Chambers, 1986 September 13 (Box 6)
  - Shroud of Turin, 1986 September 17 (Box 6)
  - Central America and South America Awareness Day, 1986 October 26 (Box 6)
  - Leonard Nimoy, 1986 November 10 (Box 6)
  - Ted Kennedy, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Pornography Forum, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Gary Hart, 1987 January 27 (Box 6)
  - Ambassador Arkaby Stevchenko, 1987 February 17 (Box 6)
  - Maki Mandela, 1987 March 3 (Box 6)
  - Elie Wiesel, 1987 September 15 (Box 6)
  - US-Persian Gulf Forum, 1987 October 6 (Box 6)
  - Jerry Falwell, 1987 October 15 (Box 6)
  - Coach K, 1987 October 28 (Box 6)
  - Forum: Distinguished Alumni, 1987 October 30 (Box 6)
  - Jeremy Rifkin, 1987 November 4 (Box 6)
  - Ron Paul, 1987 December 7 (Box 7)
  - Zbigniew Brzezinski, 1987 December 9 (Box 7)
  - Sex Seminar, 1987 (Box 7)
  - Homecoming Alumni Forum, 1987-1988 (Box 7)
  - Senator Sanford/Tom Walker, 1987-1988 (Box 7)
  - Washington Trip, 1987-1988 (Box 7)
  - Jerry Levin, 1988 January 28 (Box 7)
  - Dick Vitale, 1988 February 3 (Box 7)
  - Allister Sparks/Alex Harris, 1988 February 16 (Box 7)
  - Yehuda Blum (Arieh Levine), 1988 February 25 (Box 7)
  - Dr. Fredrick van Zyl Slabbert, 1988 Febraury 28 (Box 7)
  - David Barber, 1988 February 29 (Box 7)
  - Judge Robert Bork, 1988 April 11 (Box 7)
  - Jesse Jackson, 1988 August 28 (Box 7)
  - Bill Bradley, 1988 September 6-8 (Box 7)
  - Lisa Birnbach, 1988 September 15 (Box 7)
  - Joe Biden, 1988 October 26 (Box 7)
  - William Sloan Coffin, 1988 October 27 (Box 7)
  - Julius Scales, 1988 November 1 (Box 7)
  - John Updike, 1988 December 1 (Box 7)
  - Elizabeth Dole, 1988 (Box 7)
  - India Symposium, 1988 (Box 7)
  - Sam Wyche, 1988-1989 (Box 7)
  - William Bennett, 1989 January 19 (Box 7)
  - Gur Ofer/Eric Green, 1989 April 12 (Box 7)
  - Allen Ginsberg, 1989 April 13 (Box 7)
  - Sarah Weddington, 1989 April 13 (Box 7)
  - Margaret Atwood, 1989 April 18 (Box 7)
  - Studs Terkel, 1989 October 10 (Box 7)
  - Peter Dean, 1989 October 20 (Box 7)
  - Errol Morris, 1989 October 20 (Box 7)
  - William Gray, 1989 October 30 (Box 7)
  - Father George Stallings, 1989 November 2 (Box 7)
  - Ann Atwater/CP Ellis, 1989 November 30 (Box 7)
  - Evon Streetman, circa 1989 (Box 7)
  - Jimmy Carter, 1989-1990 (Box 7)
  - Nancy Hanks, 1989-1990 (Box 7)
  - Alice Walker, 1989-1990 (Box 7)
  - Last Lecture Series, 1989-1990 (Box 7)
  - Ethics in America Symposium, 1989-1990 (Box 7)
  - Reynolds Price/Robert Coles, 1990 January 23 (Box 7)
  - Frontiers of Legal Thought Conference, 1990 January 25-27 (Box 7)
  - Michael and Grainne Yeats, 1990 February 19 (Box 7)
  - Lenora Fulani, 1990 February 19 (Box 7)
  - Teach for America play, 1990 March 21 (Box 7)
  - Henry Cho, 1990 March 29 (Box 7)
  - Spike Lee, 1990 March 30 (Box 7)
  - Jana Moveslava, 1990-1991 (Box 8)
  - Walter Kronkite, undated (Box 8)
  - George F. Will, 1991 February 18 (Box 8)
  - Andrew Young, 1991 February 28 (Box 8)
  - Abba Eban, 1991 April 9 (Box 8)
  - Jeanne Kirkpatrick, 1991 March 26 (Box 8)
  - Randy Cohen, 1991 September 19 (Box 8)
  - PJ O'Rourke, 1991 October 1 (Box 8)
  - Phil Nee, 1991 October 2 (Box 8)
  - Doug Marlette, 1991 October 10 (Box 8)
  - Richard Gephardt, 1991 November 14 (Box 8)
  - Nancy Zeigenmeyer, 1991 November 20 (Box 8)
  - Phil Nee, 1991 October 2 (Box 8)
  - Bush/Quayle Campaign, 1991-1992 (Box 8)
  - Dick Cheney, 1991-1992 (Box 8)
  - John Sununu, 1991-1992 (Box 8)
  - Chuck D, 1992 January 29 (Box 8)
  - Oliver Stone, 1992 April 6 (Box 8)
  - Pat Buchanen, 1992 April 29 (Box 8)
  - Jerry Brown, 1992 May 2 (Box 8)
  - Jacob Holdt, 1992 September 16 (Box 8)
  - Chris Connelly, 1992 September 23 (Box 8)
  - Samuel Lewis, 1992 October 14 (Box 8)
  - Bosnia and Herzegovina, 1992 October 30 (Box 8)
  - Pat Schroeder, 1992 November 9 (Box 8)
  - Coach K, 1992 November 12 (Box 8)
  - William Greider, 1992 November 19 (Box 8)
  - Senator Ted Kennedy, 1992 December 2 (Box 8)
  - Clinton/Gore Campaign, 1992-1993 (Box 8)
  - Bob Costas, 1992-1993 (Box 8)
  - Mi Gente: Carlos Fuentes-Carbonell, 1992-1993 (Box 8)
  - Greenpeace, 1992-1993 (Box 8)
  - Kurt Vonnegut, 1992-1993 (Box 8)
  - Frontiers of Legal Thought, 1993 January 21-24 (Box 8)
  - Akasha (Gloria) Hull, 1993 March 3 (Box 8)
  - Naomi Wolf, 1993 March 31 (Box 8)
  - Amiri Baraka, 1993 April 8 (Box 8)
  - Tsongas/Rudman, 1993 January 24 (Box 8)
  - Jesse Jackson, 1993 March 9 (Box 8)
  - Ren & Stimpy - Billy West, 1993 April 14 (Box 8)
  - Hunter Thompson, 1993 April 14 (Box 8)
  - Richard Roth, 1993 April 20 (Box 9)
  - Colman McCarthy, 1993 April 15 (Box 9)
  - Women of Color Series, 1993 Spring (Box 9)
  - Gil White, 1993 October 8 (Box 9)
  - Dr. Shelby Steele, 1993 November 4 (Box 9)
  - Ken Kesey, 1993 November 16 (Box 9)
  - Oliver Stone, 1993 December 3 (Box 9)
  - Benjamin Barber, 1993-1994 (Box 9)
  - Joe Biden, 1993-1994 (Box 9)
  - Jonathan Demme, 1993-1994 (Box 9)
  - Carol Moseley-Brown, 1993-1994 (Box 9)
  - Joe Clark, 1994 February 2 (Box 9)
  - Tsongas, 1994 February 24 (Box 9)
  - Anna Quindlen, 1994 March 18 (Box 9)
  - Naomi Wolf, 1994 March 18 (Box 9)
  - Prime Minister Janez Drnovszek [cancelled], 1994 April 6 (Box 9)
  - Colonel Margarethe Cammermeyer, 1994 November 15 (Box 9)
  - Richard Roth, 1994-1995 (Box 9)
  - Co-sponsored Minor Speakers, 1994-1995 (Box 9)
  - Kurt Vonnegut, 1996 March 26 (Box 9)
  - Nadine Strossen, 1996 October 2 (Box 9)
  - John Douglas, 1996 November 19 (Box 9)
  - Mary Fisher, 1996 December 5 (Box 9)
  - Marian Marzynski, 1997 February 12 (Box 9)
  - Nancy Mairs, 1997 April 15 (Box 9)
- Publicity
  - Senator Mark O. Hatfield, Sept. 26 [year unknown] (Box Oversize Folder 1)
  - James J. Kilpatrick, Sept. 29 [year unknown] (Box Oversize Folder 1)
  - Dr. JB Rhine, Feb. 24 [year unknown] (Box Oversize Folder 1)
  - Panel, "Emphasis: The South," March 3, 10, 17 [year unknown] (Box Oversize Folder 1)
  - Shelby Steele; Mike Krzyzewski; Ken Kesey; Oliver Stone, Nov.-Dec. [year unknown] (Box Oversize Folder 1)
  - Dr. Robert A. Van Kluyve, 1969 Apr. 21 (Box Oversize Folder 1)
  - Clovis Maksoud, 1978 Apr. 3 (Box Oversize Folder 1)
  - George Plimpton, 1979 Nov. 6 (Box Oversize Folder 1)